Good afternoon everyone. Well, with some of you about to go out on field work,
大家下午好。你们中的一些人即将去实地考察，
it's timely  that in this afternoon's session I'll be sharing some ideas about the reasons
是时候在今天下午的课上讲讲
why groups of whales and dolphins sometimes swim ashore from the sea right onto the beach and, most often, die in what are know as 'mass strandings'.
为什么成群的鲸鱼和海豚会从大海游上海岸，并经常死于大规模的搁浅了。
Unfortunately, this type of event is a frequent occurrence in some of the locations that you'll be travelling to,
不幸的是，这种事情经常发生在你去游览的地方。
where sometimes the tide goes out suddenly, confusing the animals.
有时，那里的潮汐突然退去会使动物感到困惑。
However, there are many other theories about the causes of mass strandings.
然而，还有许多其他关于大规模搁浅成因的理论。
The first is that the behaviour is linked to parasites.
首先是这种行为与寄生虫有关。
It's often found that stranded animals were infested with large numbers of parasites.
经常发现搁浅的动物受到大量寄生虫的感染。
For instance, a type of worm is commonly found in the ears of dead whales.
例如，一种虫子经常能在死鲸鱼的耳朵里找到。
Since marine animals rely heavily on their hearing to naviqate, this type of infestation has the notential to be very harmful.
由于海洋动物主要靠听力导航，这种感染的潜在危害很大。
Another theory is related to toxins, or poisons.
另一种理论与毒素或毒药有关。
These have also been found to contribute to the death of many marine animals.
这些也导致了许多海洋生物的死亡。
Many toxins, as I'm sure you're aware, originate from plants, or animals.
我想你们也知道，许多毒素来源于植物和动物。
The whale ingests these toxins in its normal feeding behaviour
鲸鱼在它们的日常摄食行为中摄取了这些毒素，
but whether these poisons directly or indirectly lead to stranding and death, seems to depend upon the toxin involved.
但是这些毒药是否直接或间接导致搁浅和死亡似乎要取决于涉及的毒素本身。
In 1988, for example, fourteen humpback whales examined after stranding along the beaches of Cape Cod
例如，在1988年有14只座头鲸在科德角海滩搁浅后
were found to have been poisoned after eating tuna that contained saxitoxin, the same toxin that can be fatal in humans.
被查出吃了含有蛤蚌毒素的金枪鱼。这种毒素对人类同样致命。